准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
新学生派大星
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
要去上驾校了
Time for boating school
开始吧  小蜗
Let it rip, Gary
哒哒
Ta-da
还不错  好搭档
Not bad, partner in crime
不过面包再烤焦一点比较好
The toasts could have been a little darker, though
再见
See you later
海绵宝宝  要去捉水母了吗
Hey, SpongeBob, want to go jelly fishing?
抱歉  派大星
Sorry, Patrick
没办法
I can't
我今天得上学
I have school today
你上学了  我一整天要怎么办
What am I supposed to do all day while you're at school?
不知道
I don't know
我走了的时候  你一般会干嘛
What do you normally do when I'm gone?
等你回来
Wait for you to get back
等一下  派大星
Wait a second, Patrick
不然你跟我一起上学吧
Why don't you come to school with me?
真是个好办法
That's a great idea
你跟我一起上学  当同学
You and me in school together as classmates
想想就快乐
Think about it
滑浪学校
准备好了  派大星
Brace yourself, Patrick
由我来为你介绍
I'm about to introduce you
一生所见最为惊险刺激的学术之旅
to the greatest academic thrill ride of your lifetime
滑浪学校
还不用排队
And no line
派大星请看  学习之走廊
Behold, Patrick, the hallway of learning
这是学习之饮水机
And here's the fountain of learning
这是学习之柜
And these are the lockers of learning
这是学习之阶梯  对吧
And these are the stairs of learning, right?
不对  普通的楼梯而已
No, they're just the stairs
这才是学习之阶梯
These are the stairs of learning
其他同学呢
Where's everyone?
不知道
I don't know
大概都在家
Home probably
九点才上课
Class doesn't start till 9:00
六点二十
6:20?
你不是说要迟到了吗
But I thought you said you were late
早到快迟到了
Late for being early
我什么时候戴的表
When did I start wearing a watch?
现在参观上课用的房间
And now for the room with the most class
教室
the classroom
这边是黑板
And here's the chalkboard
可以为我们取一瓢知识之饮
It's the ladle that helps us
drink from the fountain of knowledge
腹中经纶有多少  全都记录在
And those drinks are recorded here
好榜样
这个好榜样光荣榜上面
on the Good Noodles Board
抱歉
Sorry
海绵宝宝
出勤
Attendance
笔迹工整
Penmanship
基本课桌卫生
Basic Desk Sanitation
进阶课桌卫生
Advanced Desk Sanitation
帮你把名字写上去
I'll add your name
这样你也就能集到好榜样之星了
so you can start collecting good noodle stars, too
好了
There you are
派大星
你星星好多啊
Look at all the stars you have
这样的高度我肯定达不到
I'll never be that good
派大星啊
Now, Patrick
我跟大家没有区别
I'm just like everyone else
星星有多少无所谓
no matter how many stars I have
七十四颗
Seventy-four
谁说的话
Who said that?
是他吗
Was it him?
那可不是
I doubt it
那是洛哥  班级科学项目
That's Roger, our class science project
他能教什么
What does he teach us?
最伟大的一课
The greatest lesson of all
生命珍贵的价值
the precious value of life
派大星  你看
You see, Patrick
蛋壳洛哥代表着一条脆弱的界限
Roger Shell represents the fragile line
分隔着船上司机的生与死
between life and death when behind the wheel of a boat
这盏灯泡代表着知识
This lightbulb represents knowledge
但凡它不再发光发热
And without its energy and warmth
洛哥几分钟不到就会没命
within minutes, Roger would die
生  死
Life, death
派大星
Patrick
抱歉
Sorry
早到最棒的优点就在于
The best part of being early is
可以坐前排  靠近老师
you get to sit close to the teacher
第二把椅子坐不坐
Think you can handle the second chair?
我等着呢
I'm waiting
一定会特别棒
This is gonna be great
同学们好
Hello, class
我是泡芙老师
My name is Mrs. Puff
我之所以会自我介绍
And the only reason I say that
是因为我们班来了一位新同学
is because I see we have a new student
同学  请你站起来自我介绍一下吧
Young man, why don't you stand up and introduce yourself
那胖小孩跟谁说话
Who's the fat kid talking to?
是跟你  派大星
You, Patrick
她就是老师
she's the teacher
来吧  把你的名字告诉同学
Come on, now, tell the class your name
别紧张
Don't be nervous
我们只是想知道你的名字
We just want to know your name
二十四
Twenty-four
太棒了  又一个天才
Great, another genius
他们笑什么
Why are they laughing?
时间刚刚好吧
I guess it's just in the timing
今天的第一课是拐弯
Today's first lesson will be on "Turning"
二十四
Twenty-four
派大星
Hey, Patrick
怎么了
What?
我想到了比二十四更好笑的笑话
I thought of something funnier than 24
说说看
Let me hear it
二十五
Twenty-five
够了
That's enough
同学  鉴于你第一天上课
Young man, this is your first day
就只给你个警告
so I'll let you off with a warning
至于你  海绵宝宝
As for you, SpongeBob
好榜样要起带头作用
I expect more from a good noodle
认真听课
Pay attention
好的  泡芙老师
Yes, Mrs. Puff
然后  拐弯
Now, then, "Turning":
红灯下拐弯
每位司机的必备知识
what every driver should know
拐弯时
When you are turning
至少十分有必要打出转向信号
it is important to signal at least
胖冬瓜
便便
"Big Fat Meanie"?
派大星  不能这样
Patrick, you can't do that
她可是老师
She's the teacher
老师怎么了
What about the teacher?
什么
What
胖冬瓜
便便
搞得好像我真长这样似的
As if I really look like this
海绵宝宝  你一定知道
SpongeBob, I believe you know
两次扰乱课堂有什么惩罚吧
the punishment for two classroom disruptions
不要
No
很抱歉  海绵宝宝
I'm sorry, SpongeBob
好榜样
海绵宝宝
但是想当好榜样
but if one wishes to be a good noodle
就必须有个好榜样的样子
one must behave like a good noodle
我是好榜样
I'm a good noodle
表现好了再还你星星
You'll get this star back when you earn it
不要
Nooo
No
泡芙老师  现在是睡觉时间吗
Mrs. Puff, is it nap time?
海绵宝宝  受不了你这样闹来闹去了
SpongeBob, I've had enough of your nonsense
东西收拾好
Now collect your things
搬到教室后排那张空座去
and move to the available desk in the back of the room
可是
But
我
me?
为什么
But why?
胖冬瓜要你搬就搬
Because the Big Fat Meanie said so
快去
Now go
真谢谢你了  派大星
Thanks a lot, Patrick
不用谢  兄弟
Sure thing, buddy
坐后排还是能当个好榜样
I guess I could be a good noodle from back here
我先前说到  左转必须要
Now, as I was saying, when turning left, you must
听不清啊
It's so hard to hear
到底什么样的同学才会坐这后排
What kind of student sits back here anyway?
傻子才上学
这是什么地方啊
Where am I?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
别理他  海绵宝宝
Just ignore him, SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  这边
SpongeBob, over here
不管干什么都别看他
Whatever you do, don't look at him
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
看这边
Over here
我要跟你说个事
I'm trying to tell you something
说个大事
Something important
什么事
What?
嗨
Hi
也许现在正好适合下课
Perhaps this would be a good time for recess
兄弟
Hey, buddy
课上可搞笑了
Funny stuff in there
可搞笑了
Funny stuff
你上课闹的事一点都不好笑  派大星
There is nothing funny
about what you did in there, Patrick
都害我惹上麻烦了
You got me in trouble
害我搬到教室后排去了
You got me moved to the back of the room
害我一颗好榜样之星没了
You cost me one of my good noodle stars
就一笨星星谁羡慕啊
Who cares about a stupid star?
派大星  貌似
Gee, Patrick, it seems like
你可羡慕笨星星了
you would care a lot about stupid stars
因为你本来就是笨星星
considering you are one
下课就找你算账
I'll deal with you after class
早就下课了
It is after class
打
Fight
没看到谁打架啊  你有看到吗
I don't see anyone fighting, do you?
他们是在说我们
They're talking about us
我们在打架
We're fighting
那我就开打了
I don't mind if I do
打
Fight
尬死我了
This is embarrassing
怎么回事
What's going on here?
怎么了
Well?
我跟海绵宝宝在打架
SpongeBob and I were fighting
打架
Fighting?
我居然会这么说
Well, I can't believe I'm saying this, but
海绵宝宝  我要处分你跟你朋友
SpongeBob Squarepants, I hereby
sentence you and your friend
留校察看
to detention
Detention?
愿海神王宽恕你们的灵魂
May Neptune have mercy on your soul
我好榜样才一天就变反面教材了
In one day I've gone from good noodle to bad egg
都是笨蛋派大星的错
It's all stupid Patrick's fault
我恨你  派大星
I hate you, Patrick
我更恨你
I hate you more
那不管怎样我都要恨你
Well, I'd hate you no matter what
是吗
Yeah?
就算我不恨你  我也要恨你
Well I'd hate you even if I didn't hate you
就算你刚说的有逻辑  我也要恨你
I'd hate you even if that made sense
就算你是我  我也要恨你
I'd hate you even if you were me
我就这么恨你
That's how much I hate you
我一定要恨你  就算是
I'd hate you if even, uh
就算让洛哥活命的灯泡灭了我也恨你
I'd hate you even if the lightbulb
keeping Roger alive went out
抱歉叫你笨星星
I'm sorry I called you a stupid star
抱歉让你惹上了麻烦
I'm sorry I got you in trouble
害你搬到了教室后排
and got you moved to the back of class
害你好榜样之星没了一颗
and got your good noodle star removed
还朝你吐纸团
and shot spitballs
抱歉你的抱歉太长了
I'm sorry your apology is so long
我也是
Me too
去救洛哥吧
Let's save Roger
我帮他保温
I'll keep him warm
你到储物间里拿灯泡
and you get a lightbulb from the supply closet
储物间
灯泡
Lightbulb
可怎么非得放这么远
But why does it have to be so far away?
我来了  海绵宝宝
I'm coming, SpongeBob
派大星呢
Where's Patrick?
算了
Forget it
我自己给洛哥保温
I've got to go find Roger some warmth
灯泡
The lightbulb
不保温洛哥会没命的
Without its warmth, Roger will die
洛哥
Roger
没了他
Without him
灯泡也没什么好保温的了
the lightbulb will have nothing to warm
成功了  派大星
We did it, Patrick
我们救活了洛哥
We saved Roger's life
你们好样的
Good job, boys
我在单向黑板后面看到了整个经过
I saw the whole thing from behind my one-way chalkboard
很高兴能看到你们齐心协力
and I couldn't be happier with your teamwork
我要给你们俩都奖励一颗金色小星星
I've decided to give you each one gold star
虽然不知道救活一颗蛋
Although, I'm not sure what saving an egg
跟滑浪学校有什么关系
has to do with boating school
滑浪学校
Boating school?
还以为这是在上西班牙语课
I thought this was Spanish class
再见  海绵宝宝
See you, SpongeBob
再见  胖冬瓜
See you, Big Fat Meanie
我错过了什么
What'd I miss?
蛤蜊
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
菜单
你更喜欢什么
What do you like better?
珊瑚碎块还是牡蛎脆皮
The coral bits or the nacho oyster skins?
都不喜欢
I like neither
能给你点餐吗
Can I take your order?
那藤壶圈呢
How about the barnacle rings?
好不好吃
Are they any good?
不好
No
你要吃什么
What will you have?
就是
Well, uh
你觉得海草
what's your vote on the kelp
先生  就这么直说吧
Sir, let's just get this out of the way
菜单上的餐我都讨厌
I hate everything on the menu
你想要什么
Now what do you want?
尝尝珊瑚碎块
Try the coral bits
我就尝尝珊瑚碎块吧
I'll try the coral bits
总共一块钱
That'll be one dollar
怎么回事
What's going on?
一定是什么傻事
Something stupid, I'm sure
看吧
See?
早说了
I told you
蟹老板怎么了
What's wrong with Mr. Krabs?
没事  小子
Nothing, lad
知道这是什么吗
Do you know what this is?
特别肮脏的一块钱
A very dirty dollar?
不对
No
这是我赚到的第一百万块钱
This is my one millionth dollar earned
每只螃蟹的蟹生目标就是赚到一百万
Every Krab's goal in life is to make a million dollars
现在我赚到了
and now I got mine
恭喜你  先生
Congratulations, sir
你刚把我赚的第一百万块钱给了我
You have just given me my one millionth dollar
好啊
Great
有什么奖吗
What do I win?
没有
Nothing
滚出去
Now get out
什么
What?
滚
Get out
全都给我滚
Everybody get out
你们坏了我的好心情
You're spoiling my moment
我第一百万块钱
My millionth dollar
恭喜你  蟹老板
Congratulations, Mr. Krabs
你们应该高兴点  小子们
Congratulate yourselves, lads
船长没了忠诚的船员  就什么都不是
A captain's nothing without his loyal crew
你们这样的员工
I mean, a crew like you
也许一生就只能遇见一次
comes along maybe once in a lifetime
为了奖励你们帮我
And to reward you for helping me
赚到了我第一百万块钱
make my millionth dollar
我要带你们去旅游
I'm taking you on a trip
旅游
A trip
真不敢相信  蟹老板
I can't believe it, Mr. Krabs
要去哪  奢华泉
Where are we going, Fancy Spring?
不对
No
荣宠岛
Pamper Island?
再猜
Try again
裤头民俗村
Bikini Bottom Folk Village
比那强多了
Better than that
钓蛤蜊
Clam fishing?
累死累活就这么个奖励
This is the reward we get for all our hard work?
在脏湖乘臭船钓臭蛤蜊
Fishing for stinky clams
in a smelly old boat on a filthy lagoon?
小气鬼号
你管这叫快乐
You call this fun?
拜托  章鱼哥
Come on now, Squidward
我们三个出海闲着没事
three fellas at sea with nothing to do
就来垂钓一下
but throw their lines in the water
钓几只蛤蜊再丢回水里
catch a few clams and then throw them back
不觉得很快乐吗
Don't you think that's fun?
不乐
No
这个时候我本来还能戴假发套的
And to think I could be wearing a powdered wig right now
章鱼哥  想不想要我在这边下钩
Hey, Squidward, you want me to cast out over here
让你尽情观赏吗
so you can watch me?
不然你就到那边下钩
How about you cast out over there
让我尽情无视你
so I can ignore you
好
Okay
挥杆小心点
Watch where you're swinging that
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
给我小心
be careful with
我受够了
Okay, I've had enough
章鱼哥  放松点
Oh, Squidward, you got to lighten up
虽然那小子钓得是有点热情过头了
Sure, the lad's a bit overeager
但是你一定要学着
but you've got to learn
从容应对
to roll with the punches
顺其自然
Go with the flow
而且上船最好别乱带东西
And don't bring anything on the boat
不然可容易丢了
that you ain't prepared to lose
我第一百万块钱
Me millionth dollar
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
别
wait
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你挥杆钩到了我第一百万块钱
you hooked me millionth dollar on the back swing
拉回来  不然我惩罚你
Reel it in before I keelhaul ya
不好了
Oh, no
海绵宝宝  快拉回来
SpongeBob, quick, reel it in
没听到音乐吗
Can't you hear the music?
那可是固定反复的四四拍D小调弦乐
That's a 4/4 string ostinato in D minor
水手都知道那意味着死亡
Every sailor knows that means death
趁早拉回来
Reel it in before it's too late
快点  海绵宝宝
Hurry, SpongeBob
音乐越奏越快了
The music's getting faster
找到你们了  一群坏蛋
There you are, you stinking bilge rats
别奏乐了
Stop playing that music
拜托别奏了
Stop it, please
算我求你们了
I'm begging you
加油啊  钱钱
Come on, honey
你能行的
You can make it
游快点
Swim faster
来我这儿  宝贝
Come to me, baby
回来吧
Come on back
海绵宝宝快点
Hurry, SpongeBob
这就来
Here she comes
拜托  拜托
Please, please
成功上来了
She made it
好耶
Yeah
刚才差点以为钱要没了
For a second or two, I thought she was a goner
旅途愉快不  蟹老板
So, some trip, hey, Mr. Krabs?
章鱼哥
Oh, Squidward
说来你们肯定不信
you're never going to believe it
有只巨型蓝唇蛤蜊
A giant blue-lipped clam
吃了我第一百万块钱
ate me millionth dollar
我钱没了
I lost me dollar
而且再也拿不回来了
and I'll never get it back
回不来  回不来
Never, never
从来没见过蟹老板这么崩溃
I've never seen Mr. Krabs so broken up
拜托
Oh, please
单纯是他爱演罢了
He's such a drama queen
真是的  蟹老板
Come on, Mr. Krabs
别演了
Drop the act
蟹老板  才一块臭钱而已
Mr. Krabs, it's just a stupid dollar
老天有眼  蟹老板
For Pete's sake, Mr. Krabs
想开点
suck it up
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
好好好  蟹老板
Okay, okay, Mr. Krabs
这就帮你把钱找回来
We'll help you get your dollar back
真的吗
You will?
好啊
Great
在这等着
Wait right here
得来认真钓蛤蜊了
Here's where clam fishing gets serious
你们负责钓
Okay, you boys man the fishing poles
我负责寻找蓝唇蛤蜊
And I'll keep me eyes peeled for Old Blue Lip
遵命  船长
Aye-aye, Captain
别忘了  要想走
And remember, we don't leave
得先抓到蛤蜊  把钱救回来
until we catch that clam and rescue me dollar
够了
That's it
我不干了
I'm finished
都漂流三天了
We've been here for three days
结果一点进展都没
and haven't gotten a nibble
没戏唱了
This is hopeless
是啊
Yeah
我还得回家喂小蜗呢
And I've got to get home to feed Gary
这下我们就要死在这了
We're going to die out here
全怪有只蛤蜊吃了蟹老板的臭钱
just because a clam ate Mr. Krabs' stupid dollar
他真想救回他的钱的话
Well, if he wants his dollar back
不然就给他钱吧
I say we give it to him
懂我意思吧
Know what I mean?
这我懂
I get you
蟹老板  蟹老板
Mr. Krabs, Mr. Krabs
看咱发现啥了
Look what we got
该不会是
Could it be?
我第一百万块钱
Me millionth dollar
等一下
Wait a minute
这不是我第一百万块钱
This isn't me millionth dollar
就一普普通通的钱
This is an ordinary dollar
稍微皱了点
that's been crumpled up
还有点破  泡了湖水
torn slightly, soaked in the lagoon
上面还有半光泽珊瑚蓝二号的口红印
and kissed with Coral Blue Number Two
Semi-gloss Lipstick
其实是珊瑚蓝三号
Actually, it's Coral Blue Number Three
我这么信任你们  却给了我这个
I trusted you, and you gave me this
我自己的员工竟然会这样背叛我
I can't believe me own crew would betray me like this
不行
No
没门
苦情戏没法动摇我们了
We will not be swayed by tears anymore
懂了
I see
那就只能玩奖励这套了
Then I guess I have no choice but to offer a reward
开什么玩笑
You're kidding?
是不是又能出来垂钓了
Is it another fishing trip?
错
No
是这个三明治
It's this sandwich
三明治
A sandwich?
居然要我为了个三明治拼命
You expect me to break my back over a sandwich?
不是随便什么三明治
Not a sandwich
是这个三明治
The sandwich
随你便
Whatever
船上可是还有不少
We've got plenty more to
吃的
eat
这下想必能相互理解了吧
Now, I think we understand each other
想吃东西
Nobody eats
先救回我第一百万块钱再说
until I get my millionth dollar back
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
能跟你说句话吗
can I have a word with you?
有没有注意到
Have you noticed
蟹老板已经完全失去理智了
that Mr. Krabs has gone completely insane?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你看看
Just look at him
逝者安息
我的第一百万块钱
章鱼哥
Squidward
他都失去跟自己最亲近的东西了
he's lost something near and dear to him
你就不能
Haven't you?
再看看
Look again
还真是
You're right
该怎么逃
How do we get out of here?
只要完全没动静
If we're real quiet
就能溜到救生船上
we can sneak over to the lifeboat
好
Okay
所以说  你们以为自己能躲过
So, you thought you'd skip out
老螃蟹的法眼  是不是啊
on old Krabs, did you?
你们可是保证过要帮我的
Even after you promised to help me
我知道你们的小心思
I know what you're thinking
就一块臭钱而已
"It's just a dumb old dollar"
直接抛弃那个老头子吧
"Let's just leave the old man"
他发现不到的
"He won't notice"
不能这样下去
Well, it's not going down like that
你们这样暗算我的员工就一个用途
There's only one use for a backstabbing crew like you
活诱饵
live bait
你疯了
You're crazy
蛤蜊这么久不来
If that clam didn't come before
你哪来的自信觉得现在会来
what makes you think he'll come now?
一定会的
He'll come
蟹老板  听我说
Mr. Krabs, listen
我整天跟海绵宝宝一块工作
I work with SpongeBob all day long
所以下面要说的这句话我非常熟
so I know what I'm talking about when I say
你完完全全疯了吧
you are completely out of your mind
放我们走
Get us out of here
过来  有新鲜的肉
Come on, fresh meat
摆起来
Keep thrashing
它喜欢
He likes it
快过来
Come on, boy
靠近点
Closer
closer
快到了
Almost there
到了
That's it
你们看
Look, boys
物归原主了
I finally got it
第一百万块钱终于回来了
I finally got me millionth dollar
可怜的蟹老板
Poor Mr. Krabs
永远离我们而去了
Gone forever out of our lives
为什么死的不是我
Why couldn't it have been me?
对啊
Yes
为什么死的不是你
Why couldn't it have been you?
为什么他会这样牺牲
Why did he have to go like this?
为什么
Why?
为什么他会这样牺牲
Why did he have to go like this
害我跟这白痴绑在一起
and leave me tied to this idiot?
你们好
Hello, boys
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
你们有没有见过
Have you boys met
我第一百万块钱
me millionth dollar?
你怎么搞回来的
How did you get it back?
这可不简单
It wasn't easy
蓝唇蛤蜊挺能打的
Old Blue Lips is quite the fighter
所以我们最后达成了交易
so eventually, we settled on a trade
你拿什么交易的
What did you give him?
那个不要紧
Nothing important